<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vulnman Project – News About Docsy</title><link>https://vulnman.github.io/blog/news/</link><description>Recent content in News About Docsy on Vulnman Project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://vulnman.github.io/blog/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog: Time to follow the Hype</title><link>https://vulnman.github.io/blog/2023/01/26/time-to-follow-the-hype/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vulnman.github.io/blog/2023/01/26/time-to-follow-the-hype/</guid><description>
&lt;p>There have been no updates and commits for vulnman for some time now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The reason is that the focus was moved to rebuild everything from scratch and follow the hype of modern frontend frameworks like VueJs.
During last month, I completly rewritten the backend part into a REST-API, learning VueJs and build a - hopefully not so ugly - new frontend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>vulnman will be deprecated once the new tool will be available.
The new version will have more advantages and can be easily integrated into other tools using its REST-API.
The database schema is a bit more flexible, more code reuse and other improvements in maintance.
There will be filters, searches and ways to order findings, projects and more, which was not done in original vulnman.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But be warned, I am not a developer and certainly not a frontend developer. ;)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The next version will be completly free and open source too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have ideas for new features, improvements or want to contribute to the new tool before it is going public, feel free to reach out to &lt;code>vulnman-project dot riseup dot net&lt;/code>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Current Development Status</title><link>https://vulnman.github.io/blog/2022/05/26/current-development-status/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vulnman.github.io/blog/2022/05/26/current-development-status/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This post is intended to give a brief summary of the current development processes and ideas in vulnman.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Currently the focus is on implementing and improving the &amp;ldquo;Responsible Disclosure&amp;rdquo; application.
There have been some bug fixes and UI improvements here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition, preparations are underway for new user roles that will be able to log in and use vulnman in the future.
Using the &amp;ldquo;Responsible Disclosure&amp;rdquo; application as an example, we are thinking of developers of the software in question.
These should be able to be invited in the future and thus receive a release for the corresponding vulnerabilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few other quick updates:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have already implemented our own user model.
This is a breaking change to version 0.3.0.
Data from version 0.3.0 will probably not be migratable.
However, this change will allow us more flexibility in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>User profiles already exist. These are currently still minimalistic, but the base is already done.
Pentester profiles are public and should be able to be changed to private in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Soon there will be a first implementation of a comment function under vulnerabilities in the RD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The page a user sees after login will differ per user role.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These will be by and large the changes in the next release.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See you soon.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: New Documentation</title><link>https://vulnman.github.io/blog/2022/05/26/new-documentation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vulnman.github.io/blog/2022/05/26/new-documentation/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://vulnman.github.io/doc">vulnman documentation&lt;/a> got a new home.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>