<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vulnman Project – User Guide</title><link>https://vulnman.github.io/docs/user-guide/</link><description>Recent content in User Guide on Vulnman Project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://vulnman.github.io/docs/user-guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Introducing the Web Interface</title><link>https://vulnman.github.io/docs/user-guide/introducing-webui/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vulnman.github.io/docs/user-guide/introducing-webui/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The web interface allows you to manage your pentest and its assets using a user interface.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can visit the vulnman server by opening your instance from within your browser.
The application needs you to be logged in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://vulnman.github.io/attachments/login-web-ui.png" alt="Login Screen">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After you logged in, you will be redirected to the list of your current (non archived) projects.
By clicking on one of the projects, you are able to &lt;em>activate&lt;/em> the project and see its details and do your work.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-dashboard">Project Dashboard&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The project dashboard is the home of your project.
It gives you a short overview about the state of your project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://vulnman.github.io/attachments/web_dashboard.png" alt="Dashboard">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It contains the remaining time for the project, different counts like how many vulnerabilities were found and open to dos are left.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can close the project through the &lt;code>X&lt;/code> button.
Closing a project makes it read-only.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If for some reasons you forgot your role in the project, you can found it here - in the top left of the dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A sidebar will be available with project related actions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-sidebar">The Sidebar&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The sidebar only contains project related links, while the top bar include &lt;em>global&lt;/em> links.
The sidebar is devided into different &lt;em>categories&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Pentest:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The pentest group contains links to your project&amp;rsquo;s dashboard, vulnerabilities, tasks, user accounts and project tokens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Assets:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this group you can create and manage your assets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Management:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This group handels links to manage the project. Currently there is just one item in here, which allows you to add or remove contributors.
It is important to know, that you need permissions to do so. By default, the project creator user will be able to remove or add contributors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Reporting:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here you can create new reports or download existing one.
You can write the management summary here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Generate Reports</title><link>https://vulnman.github.io/docs/user-guide/report-generation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vulnman.github.io/docs/user-guide/report-generation/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The reports in vulnman are generated from templates.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A simple default template is included, but you may want to &lt;a href="https://vulnman.github.io/docs/advanced-topics/report-templates/">customize&lt;/a> it to make it yours.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="report-list">Report List&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can have multiple reports for your projects, in case your customer wants to have for example an english, and a german report.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://vulnman.github.io/attachments/project-report-list.png" alt="Project Reports">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="new-reports">New Reports&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To create a new report, you need to give vulnman some information about the report.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;code>name&lt;/code> is just for internal purposes and is displayed in the report list.
The &lt;code>author&lt;/code> of the report is displayed in the report.
The &lt;code>title&lt;/code> field is optional and can be used to overwrite the default report title.
You can also choose a report template and language.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://vulnman.github.io/attachments/project-report-create.png" alt="Create Report">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-report">The Report&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The report requires you to write a management summary using the &lt;code>Evaluation&lt;/code> and &lt;code>Recommendation&lt;/code> fields.
Both fields will send a request to the API once you remove the focus of the fields and the content will be stored in the database.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://vulnman.github.io/attachments/project-report.png" alt="Report">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="report-releases">Report Releases&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A report release is a fixed state of the report.
Once you create a report release the report generator will use the most current information and generates the report.
If you add new vulnerabilities or edit the management summary, you need to create a new report release.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://vulnman.github.io/attachments/report-release-list.png" alt="Report Releases">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note:&lt;/strong> There is currently no status indicator of the build process. Depending on the project size, the generation may need some time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the report is created, you can click the download button to receive the generated PDF report.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Report releases can have different &lt;em>types&lt;/em>.
The &lt;code>draft&lt;/code> contains a watermark which indicates, that this report is actually a draft report.
The &lt;code>release&lt;/code> does not have a watermark.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Using The Responsible Disclosure Application</title><link>https://vulnman.github.io/docs/user-guide/responsible-disclosure-application-usage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vulnman.github.io/docs/user-guide/responsible-disclosure-application-usage/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info">
Your instance must have the responsible disclosure application feature enabled, otherwise it will not be accessible for you.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="vulnerability-listing">Vulnerability Listing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Visiting the &lt;a href="https://vulnman.github.io/docs/glossary/responsible-disclosure-app">Responsible Disclosure Application&lt;/a> opens up your list of vulnerabilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This list contains all vulnerabilities that you have created or that have been shared with you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://vulnman.github.io/attachments/rd-vuln-list.png" alt="Vulnerability List">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The default view is to show only open findings, while you can easily view closed ones by clicking the corresponding button.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="vulnerability-details">Vulnerability Details&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you click on one of the vulnerabilities in your list, you will see a screen similiar to the one below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://vulnman.github.io/attachments/rd-single-vuln.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A second navigatation bar appears which contains pages related to the vulnerability including a disclosure timeline, comments and access management.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have permissions to change the vulnerability you will find some buttons on the right to manage the vulnerability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The buttons have the following functionality (from left to right):&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Download the vulnerability details as a PDF report&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Export the vulnerability details as a Markdown advisory&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Notify vendor by mail, with PDF report attached (&lt;strong>Warning: The mail will be send unencrypted. PGP or other encryption is not yet supported!&lt;/strong>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Edit the vulnerability details&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Delete the vulnerability&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>In the bottom half of the page, you see two more buttons for adding new proofs to the vulnerability.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="proofs">Proofs&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To create a new proof, just click on one of the buttons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://vulnman.github.io/attachments/rd-create-proof.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As you can see in the screenshot, you can use markdown.
You can highlight specific parts of a codeblock with &lt;code>§§highlighted$$&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have created the proof, the proof will appear on the vulnerability details page as shown below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://vulnman.github.io/attachments/rd-single-vuln-with-proof.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="timeline">Timeline&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The timeline allows you and the vendor to track the process of the disclosure process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://vulnman.github.io/attachments/rd-timeline.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can create new &lt;em>events&lt;/em> using the button on the right corner.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="comments">Comments&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you shared the vulnerability with a user, you can use the comment feature to discuss further things about the disclosure process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://vulnman.github.io/attachments/rd-comments.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can use markdown in the comments too.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="manage-access">Manage Access&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To share the vulnerability with the vendor or other contributors you need the &lt;em>Manage Access&lt;/em> page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The pages shows who has access to the vulnerability details.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://vulnman.github.io/attachments/rd-manage-access.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can share the vulnerability by providing an email address.
If this address already belongs to a vulnman user, he will be granted the corresponding permissions.
Otherwise, an inactive user account will be created for the user with a random username.
An invitation email will be sent to the email address to activate the account and set a password.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>